어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!
홋카이도에 건너온 무사시 일행은 닌자들에게 쫒기던 사람들을 도왔다.
After crossing to Hokkaido, Musashi and his friends helped people being chased by ninjas.
그리고 바이켄 형제와 함께 포장마차를 끌고, 겐운사이가 거느리던 이하 닌자군과 싸워, 그들을 쓰러뜨렸다.
With Baiken brothers, they pulled the covered wagon, fought with Iga Ninja Forces under Gen'unsai, and took them down.
쿠콰쾅!
카라쿠리 성채이오
Kaboom!
Karakuri Stronghold
아, 춥소. 막 춥소!
It's cold-dasu! So cold-dasu!
아, 얼겠소!
I'm gonna freeze-dasu!
시끄러워, 무사시! 적어도 무예가라는 놈이 춥다고 징징대면 안 된다!
Be quiet, Musashi! A martial artist must not complain about cold weather!
뭐, 뭣이오, 센짱?!
W- what is it-dasu, Sen-chan?!
고, 곰이야!
A- a bear!
으악! 빨리 죽은 척 하시오!
Hurry up and play dead-dasu!
아, 나 맛 없소.
I- I'm not tasty-dasu.
센히메님.
Senhime.
어? 곰이 말했소!
Huh? That bear just spoke-dasu!
당신은?
Who are you?
주베 님이 보내신 사신입니다.
My master Jūbē has sent me as a messenger.
모든 건 여기에.
Everything is written here.
사람을 찾는데 그러면 안 되오!
That's a bad way of finding someone-dasu!
십년은 감수했소!
You surprised me so much-dasu!
주베 님이 뭐라고?
What did Mr. Jūbē write?
센히메님을 없애 버리고자 하는 음모는 한조의 짓이라 판명.
It became clear that the plot of removing Senhime is done by Hanzo.
뭐라!
What?!
그 한조가?
That Hanzo?
주베 님이 왜 여기에?
Why did you come, Mr. Jūbē?
한조 님께 찾아뵐 일이 있어서 왔습니다.
I am here to inquire you about something.
호오, 그건 무슨 의미일지요.
Interesting. So what is it?
이에야스 님이 오셨으니 직접 말씀하시지요.
As our Lord Ieyasu is here, you'd want to talk to him directly.
이에야스 님 행차하신다!
Lord Ieyasu is visiting!
급하게 부르셔서 찾아뵈었습니다. 무엇이든지 이 한조에게 분부만 하십시오.
Since you've called me, I'm ready to do whatever you order.
좋다. 실은, 한조, 자네에게 묻고자 하는 게 있다.
Well then. Hanzo, I have something to ask you.
예. 무엇입니까?
Yessir. What is it?
자네는 내 손녀인 센히메를 여러 번 공격해, 유괴하려고 했다고 들었는데 사실인가.
I heard that you've tried to attack and kidnap my granddaughter Senhime numerous times. Is that true?
사실이 아닙니다. 제가 어째서 그런 일을.
It is not true. Why would I do that?
사실이 아니라는 건가?
You're saying that it is false?
예.
Yessir.
분명 저를 계략에 걸리게 하려는 패거리의 날조입니다.
It is nothing more than a fabrication of a party, trying to make me fall into a scheme.
이 카라쿠리 매는 네가 부하와 긴급 연락을 하기 위해 쓰고 있던 것이다.
You have been using this Karakuri Hawk to urgently communicate with your subordinates.
무사시, 코지로를 베고, 센히메님을 탈취하라는 지령이었군.
There was a directive to cut Musashi and Kojirō, and steal Senhime.
한조. 모든 것은 주베가 조사하여 명확하다. 미련 없이 할복해라.
Hanzo, everything is clear as Jūbē investigated about this. Disembowel yourself to reclaim yourself.
들켰으니 어쩔 수 없군.
It can't be helped as you've found out.
드디어 정체를 드러냈구나, 한조! 반역자는 베어 버리겠다!
You've finally showed yourself, Hanzo! I will cut down an insurgent!
닥쳐라! 이에야스를 쓰러뜨리고 지팡구를 이 손으로 지배하는 게 내 목적.
Shut up! Taking down Ieyasu and ruling over the whole Jipangu is my objective.
그 야망은 단연코 때려 으깨주겠다!
I will smash your treasonous ambition!
야규 신영류, 역풍의 대도!
Yakyū Shinkage style, Long Sword of Headwind!
젠장!
Damn!
한조, 각오해라!
Prepare yourself, Hanzo!
무르군!
How naive!
다들 모여라! 반역자다!
Everyone gather! A treachery!
네놈들을 지옥에 보내 주겠다. 먼저 센히메부터다!
I will send all of you to hell. That begins with Senhime!
네놈!
That bastard!
센히메가 걱정되는군, 주베.
I am worried about Senhime, Jūbē.
예! 바로 만나러 가겠습니다.
Yessir! I will go meet her right away.
한조가 그런 짓을.
How dare Hanzo do that.
예. 한조 놈들은 진작에 여기 홋카이도에 건너온 듯 합니다. 조심해 주세요.
Yessir. Hanzo and his subordinates seem to be already at Hokkaido. Please be careful.
주베 님도 바로 만나러 오시고 계십니다.
My master Jūbē is coming to meet you at the moment.
알겠습니다.
Understood.
공주님!
Princess!
무사시! 왔다!
Musashi! They're here!
그렇소!
Got it!
네놈들! 멋진 척 해도 소용없소!
You guys! Acting cool won't get you anywhere-dasu!
이천일류 철풍차!
Nitenichiryu: Iron Windmill!
네놈들! 달아나는 건 비겁하오! 나와 승부를 보시오!
You bastards! Running away is cowardly-dasu! Have a match with me-dasu!
혼자 날뛰지 마라, 무사시. 방금 것은 연습이었을 것이다.
Don't act hastily, Musashi! That was a tryout.
한조가 주변에 있을까.
I wonder if Hanzo is nearby.
분명.
Probably.
좋소. 숨은 곳을 알아내서 때려부수어 주겠소!
Well then. We'll find out his hideout and smash it completely-dasu!
센히메 님, 괜찮습니까.
Senhime, are you alright?
지쳤어. 조금만 쉬자.
I'm tired. Let's take a break.
예.
Yessir.
무사시!
Musashi!
뭣이오?
What is it-dasu?
센히메 님이 지치셨다. 설동을 파서 조금 쉬자.
Senhime is tired. Let's dig a snow hole and take a break.
알겠소.
Understood-dasu.
-어?
-뭔 일이냐?
-Huh?
-What's wrong?
누군가의 목소리가 들리오.
I can hear somebody-dasu.
나, 잠깐 보고 오오!
I'll go take a look-dasu!
무사시! 잠깐!
Musashi! Stop!
누구 있소?!
Is somebody there-dasu?
어?
Huh?
도와줘... 부탁이야... 도와줘... 도와줘...
Help... please... help... help...
잠깐 기다리시오! 지금 가오!
Just a moment-dasu! I'll be right there-dasu!
이상하오.
Something's not right-dasu.
위험했소!
That was close-dasu!
오니히메! 요술로 날 속였겠소!
Onihime! You deceived me with your magic-dasu!
흥. 지금 알아채봤자 늦다, 무사시.
Hmph. You are too late for that, Musashi.
각오해라!
Prepare yourself!
오니히메! 내가 상대해 주겠다.
Onihime! I will face you.
달아났는가...
She ran away...
오니히메.
Onihime.
그녀는 뭔가 불행을 짊어지고 있는 것 같군.
It seems that she's under some kind of misery.
코지로! 멋진 척 작작 하고 빨리 구하러 오시오!
Kojirō! Quit your showing off and come to rescue me right now-dasu!
미안.
Sorry.
정말!
Really!
까딱하면 떨어질 뻔했소!
I was gonna fall-dasu!
흥. 그건 네가 멍청하니까다.
Hmph. That's because you're an imbecile.
멍청한 건 뭣이오, 멍청한 건!
What do you mean by that imbecile-dasu?!
속은 네 잘못이다.
It's all your fault for being fooled.
나는 순수하니까 쉽게 속소!
I get fooled easily because I'm pure-dasu!
센히메 님!
Senhime!
멈춰라, 오니히메!
Stop, Onihime!
센짱을 돌려주시오!
Give Sen-chan back-dasu!
성가신 놈들. 그렇지만 여기까지다!
Aren't you annoying. But that's as far as you go!
눈사태다!
A snowslide!
내가 대드니까 이렇게 되지.
This is because you defied me.
그 대단한 코지로와 무사시도 눈사태 앞에서는 이러지도 저러지도 못했다.
That mighty Kojirō and Musashi couldn't do anything in front of a snowslide.
그 쯤, 한조는 카라쿠리 요새에 있었다.
Meanwhile, Hanzo was at Karakuri Stronghold.
한조 님. 카라쿠리 요새에 온 것을 환영합니다.
Lord Hanzo. Welcome to Karakuri Stronghold.
좋다, 지라이얀. 훌륭한 요새, 마음에 들었다.
Good job, Jiraiyan. I like this perfect stronghold.
황송합니다.
I am grateful.
이에야스 놈을 놓친 건 유감이지만 이 홋카이도를 거점으로서 내 손에 지팡구를 넣기 위한 전투를 시작한다!
It's too bad that I couldn't get Ieyasu at that time, but anyway we'll begin the war to bring Jipangu into my hands!
예!
Yessir!
한조 님.
Lord Hanzo.
오, 오니히메.
Onihime.
센히메를 잡아왔습니다.
I've caught Senhime.
오, 잘 했다. 근데 무사시와 코지로는?
Good job, But what about Musashi and Kojirō?
눈사태와 함께.
They're under a snowslide.
좋다. 일단 처형된 것 같군. 무사시 놈들이 만일 온다면 센히메를 미끼로 해야겠어.
Good. They're as good as gone. But if Musashi and Kojirō appear, we'll use Senhime as a bait.
결국 잡히고 만 센히메.
Senhime has finally been captured.
눈사태에 휩쓸린 무사시와 코지로의 운명은? 카라쿠리 요새는 지옥의 입구가 되는가?
What will happen to Musashi and Kojirō swallowed up by a snowslide? Will Karakuri Stronghold be an entrance to hell?
질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
엄청 춥소. 까딱하단 얼음덩어리가 되어버릴 뻔했소.
So cold-dasu. I might have ended up as an ice-dasu.
센짱! 코지로! 어디이오!
Sen-chan! Kojirō! Where are you-dasu?!
센짱은 빼앗겼고 코지로는 행방불명...
Sen-chan has been taken away and Kojirō's nowhere to be found-dasu...
이걸 어쩌오?
What should I do now-dasu?
이 자식, 닌자 놈! 각오하시오!
You ninja bastard! Prepare yourself-dasu!
눈 뒤집히지 마라, 무사시!
Don't lose your mind, Musashi!
코지로!
Kojirō!
놀래키지 마시오!
Don't surprise me like that-dasu!
그건 내가 할 말이다!
That's my line!
멍청한 주제에 경솔한 덜렁이가!
You're a stupid fidget who happens to be also thoughtless!
뭣이오?! 의미는 잘 모르겠지만 날 바보 취급하고 있겠소!
What-dasu?! I don't understand what you're saying, but you're treating me like a fool!
그 걸핏하면 뚜껑 열리는 단세포같은 성격이 마치 꽃발게와 같구나!
Your monad-like character of blowing your top like an instant water over-heater is just like a fiddler crab!
너야말로 굴착기인 양 멍청한 모습이나 하고 있는 게 참 아니꼽소!
Your moronic excavator-like figure is really snobby-dasu!
뭐야?!
What did you say?!
해 볼 셈이오?
Wanna fight-dasu?!
힣.
Tee-hee.
이랴!
Take this!
임마, 무사시! 멈춰라!
Hey, Musashi! Stop!
했겠다!
You really did it!
이 자식!
You bastard!
이 정도야!
This is nothing!
먹으시오!
Take this-dasu!
이게! 이게! 이게!
You! Damn! Brat!
그 정도로는 안 되오!
That's never gonna work!
어? 무사시! 이런 짓이나 하고 있을 때가 아냐!
Huh? Musashi! This is not a good time to be doing this!
그렇소. 센짱을 구하는 게 먼저이오.
That's right-dasu. Rescuing Sen-chan comes first-dasu.
오니히메는 맞은편에 간 것 같다. 발자국을 찾아라!
Onihime went to the other side. Find her footsteps!
좋소!
Got it!
이건 곰의 발자국이오.
These are footsteps of a bear-dasu.
음...
Hmm...
저기엔 새 발자국 하나가 있다. 거긴 어떠냐?
There is nothing more than one bird footstep. How about your side?
곰 발자국이 있을 뿐이오. 오니히메의 발자국은 안 보이오.
Only some footsteps of a bear-dasu. I can't find Onihime's footsteps-dasu.
그렇군. 이상하네.
I see. That's not right.
어?
Huh?
이거다!
This is it!
어?
Huh?
이 발자국을 잘 봐라!
Take a look at these footsteps!
음?
Hm?
곰은 네 발로 걷는다. 게다가 이 정도의 보폭은 아니지!
A bear walks with four legs. Moreover, its pace isn't this wide!
네 발로 걷소.
Walking with four legs...
곰 발자국을 남겨서...
She left bear footsteps...
그래. 우리를 속일 생각이었겠지만 그렇게는 안 되지.
Yes. She tried to fool us, but we won't be fooled.
코지로 머리 좋소.
Kojirō, aren't you clever-dasu.
물론이지.
Of course.
이제 깨달았으니 쫒소!
As we've found that out now, let's chase-dasu!
그래.
Yes.
왔군, 무사시, 코지로! 일단 환영해 주지.
So you've appeared, Musashi and Kojirō! Let me greet you first.
가자! 케로키치!
Let's go, Kerokichi!
넌 지라이얀!
You are Jiraiyan!
전엔 퇴각했지만 오늘은 복수해 주겠다.
You might made me retreat last time, but I'm paying that back today.
먹어라!
Take this!
네이놈!
You bastard!
꽤 하는군, 코지로. 그렇지만 거기까지다.
Aren't you pretty good, Kojirō? But that will be your last.
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, 대설풍술!
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, technique of big snowstorm!
그런 요술에는 안 당하오!
A trick like that won't work against me-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
여흥은 여기까지다. 그럼!
Playtime is over. Farewell!
지라이얀. 무서운 놈.
Jiraiyan. What a terrifying brat.
무사시. 멍청한 놈.
Musashi. What a stupid brat.
아프오! 뭔 짓이오!
It hurts-dasu! What was that for-dasu?!
무사시! 쓸데없는 소리 하고 있을 때가 아니다! 서둘러라!
Musashi! This is not a time for a chatter! Hurry!
알겠소!
Got it-dasu!
-놓치지 마라!
-알고 있소!
-Don't let him get away!
-I know that-dasu!
놓쳐버렸소!
We lost him-dasu!
아니, 이 주변인 게 틀림없다.
No. They must be around here.
저건?
What's that?
한조 일당의 요새임이 틀림없다.
It must be Hanzo gang's stronghold.
여기 있겠소, 센짱도.
Sen-chan must be here-dasu, too.
그래. 무슨 일이 있어도 구해야 한다!
Yes. We must rescue her no matter what!
왔구나, 무사시, 코지로.
So you're here, Musashi and Kojirō.
내 사천왕 중 둘이나 쓰러뜨린 미운 놈.
Those abominable bastards who took two of my Four Iga Kings.
고에몬도와 슈텐의 원한은 오늘로 꽉 갚아 주겠다!
They will pay for the hatred of Goemondo and Shuten!
주베 님에 우시와카 님! 어라, 벤케이 님까지!
Mr. Jūbē and Mr. Ushiwaka! Hey, even Mr. Benkei's there!
바이켄 님!
Mr. Baiken!
무예 대회 이후 처음이구려.
It's first time we meet again ever since the competition.
그려, 오랜만이네요! 그래도 다 모여서 홋카이도에는 무슨 일로?
Yeah, it's been a while! But why would all of you gather at Hokkaido?
사실은 센히메 님의 발자국을 발자취를 따라왔습니다.
Actually, we've followed Senhime's course.
그거라면 어제 대설사에 향했수.
They are heading to Daisetsusha from yesterday.
대설사?
Daisetsusha?
먼저 서두르겠습니다. 죄송.
We'll have to hurry. Excuse us.
아, 잠깐! 무슨 일이여?
Hey, wait! What's going on here?
한조가 반역을 저질러 센히메 님 일행이 위험에 처했다고 합니다.
Hanzo has done treachery, and Senhime and others are in danger.
뭐라!
What?!
우린 주베 님께 이야기를 들어 같이 가던 참이요.
We've heard that from Mr. Jūbē, and we're going along with him.
그랬구나!
So that was it!
그럼 이만!
Then, excuse us!
바이켄은 생각했다. 무사시와의 우정을 위해서라면 지금 당장 구하러 갔을 터였다.
Baiken thought. For the sake of the friendship with Musashi, he would went to save him right away.
그렇지만 어린 형제는 평화로운 생활을 막 시작했을 뿐이었다.
But his young siblings have just begun having a peaceful life.
그 생활을 버릴 수는 없었다.
He couldn't throw that life away.
여기, 형! 이거!
Here, brother! You can take this!
잇켄!
Ikken!
갔다 와, 형!
See you later, brother!
니켄!
Niken!
여기, 도시락! 배고프면 먹어!
Here's your lunch box! Open it when you're hungry!
오하루!
Oharu!
고맙다, 모두! 형은 무사시와의 우정을 위해서 갔다 오겠어!
Thank you, everyone! I'm going for the friendship with Musashi!
건강히 기다리고 있어라!
Wait for me, without getting sick!
-형!
-오빠!
Brother!
가자, 무사시.
Let's go, Musashi.
좋소!
Got it-dasu!
거기까지다, 무사시, 코지로!
That's as far as you go, Musashi and Kojirō!
먼저 둘 다 칼을 떨어뜨려라.
First, put your swords down.
개소리 마시오! 여기에 와서 정정당당하게 승부를 보시오!
Don't be absurd-dasu! Get down to here and have a match fair and square-dasu!
그럴 필요는 없다. 이걸 봐라!
I have no need for that. Take a look at this!
센짱!
Sen-chan!
무사시... 코지로...
Musashi... Kojirō...
둘 다 칼을 떨어뜨려라.
Both of you, drop your swords.
그러지 않으면 센히메의 생명은 없다.
If you don't, Senhime is no more.
이놈들! 비겁한 짓은 때려치시오!
You bastards! Quit with your cowardly actions-dasu!
자, 어쩔래? 칼 떨어뜨릴래, 센히메 죽일래?
Oh, what would you do? Drop your swords, or kill Senhime?
이 자가 말하는 걸 믿으면 안 됩니다.
You must not trust what they're saying.
무사시, 코지로, 싸우세요.
Musashi. Kojirō. Fight.
센짱...
Sen-chan...
센히메 님!
Senhime!
난 여러분 덕분에 태어나서 처음으로 자유로운 여행을 할 수 있어 행복했습니다. 여기서 죽어도 후회는 없습니다.
I could travel freely for the first time ever since I was born thanks to you two. I have no regrets even if I die here.
센짱!
Sen-chan!
무사시는 바보에 덜렁대며 먹보였으니까 참 즐거웠어요. 코지로는 아니꼬워도 강하고 믿음직스러웠어요.
Musashi was a stupid fidgeting glutton, and that made the trip enjoyable. Kojirō was pompous yet strong and dependable.
센짱! 나도 같이 죽소!
Senchan! I'll die with you-dasu!
그럼 코지로, 넌 어쩔래?
Then, Kojirō, what's your choice?
나도 목숨은 아깝지 않다. 다만, 센히메 님의 목숨은 구해 줘라.
I also do not value my life. But instead, keep Senhime alive.
약속하지.
I promise.
절체절명의 때가 왔다. 옴싹달싹도 못하는 무사시와 코지로.
A desperate moment has come. Musashi and Kojirō can't do a thing.
센히메를 무사하게 구할 수 있을까.
Will they manage to rescue Senhime safely?
그 쯤, 주베 일행은 대설사에 향하고 있었다.
At that moment, Jūbē's group was heading to Daisetsusha.
구름이 짙게 낀 홋카이도의 땅에 무사시의 이도류, 과연 살아남을 것인가?
On the land of deeply cloudy Hokkaido, will Musashi's dual blade survive?
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't worry too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep going! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
얼음이 잔뜩 있는 홋카이도.
Hokkaido is full of ice.
춥소! 몸도 얼어버리겠소!
It's cold! My body is freezing-dasu!
주베 씨에 우시와카, 벤케이, 바이켄도 가세해서 대결전!
Mr. Jūbē, Ushiwaka, Benkei, and Baiken have joined the fight and it's a big battle!
오니히메, 지라이얀, 한조의 조무래기까지 상대해야 해서 큰일!
Facing Onihime, Jiraiyan, and Hanzo's lackies at once is difficult!
센짱을 구하는 건 가능할지 모르겠소!
I wonder if it's possible to rescue Sen-chan-dasu!
다음 이야기! 얼음도 녹이는 우정 파워이오
Next story! Ice-Melting Power of Friendship
질풍노도의 카라쿠리 요새이오!
It's a stormy Karakuri Stronghold-dasu!
다음 이야기
얼음도 녹이는
우정 파워이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Ice-Melting
Power of Friendship
Look forwards for it!